efile.com 2012-05-23

# Tax Information Privacy, Tax Data Security, Tax Laws | efile

EFILE LLC (hereinafter referred to as "EFILE") is committed to keeping your tax information private and recognizing the importance customers place on the privacy and confidentiality of their information. While new technologies allow us to more efficiently serve our clients, we are committed to maintaining the rigorous privacy standards that are synonymous with our established and trusted name.

We provide our Privacy Policy to explain our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. Our Privacy Policy is available throughout the website, as well as on our tax screens within the tax program.

EFILE adheres to Federal and State regulations to ensure the security and confidentiality of personal information you share with us during your tax preparation and efile process. We are committed to respecting and protecting your online privacy and recognize your need for appropriate protection and management of any personally identifiable or tax related information you share with us.  Your tax return information will be treated with extreme care and confidentiality. EFILE strives to comply with all applicable U.S. tax laws to protect your privacy. Our goal is to provide protection for your personal information no matter where that personal information is collected, transferred, or retained.

EFILE partners with third parties to provide tax and financial services. When users sign up for these particular services, users are requested to accept third party user agreements. If necessary, EFILE shares names or other information required by third parties to provide these services. These third parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the purpose of providing these services.

## Covered Web Sites

The Privacy Policy described herein is applicable to this entire web site, including all areas where financial information is gathered and income tax data is input, printed, and/or transmitted. It does not apply to any other online services, or to any other web sites published and/or maintained by us.

This Privacy Policy covers all the online information practices of www.efile.com. Other sites maintained by EFILE operate under their own Privacy and security policies. Third party web sites operate under their own Privacy and security policies.

top

## The efile.com Commitment to Data Security

To prevent unauthorized access, maintain data accuracy, and ensure the correct use of information, we have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.

## Internal Controls

When collecting, storing, and retrieving your personal data, extensive internal controls are maintained throughout the process to ensure security and confidentiality.

Our Internet-based systems are protected behind firewalls, and all mission critical servers are deployed in a cluster environment to provide an even greater level of security and protection against system failure. All data is maintained and backed-up on a regular schedule to provide adequate redundancy and ensure that the integrity of information is never jeopardized.

Some of our pages utilize "cookies" and other tracking technologies. A "cookie" is a small text file that may be used, for example, to collect information about web site activity. Some cookies and other technologies may serve to recall personal information previously indicated by a web user. Most browsers allow you to control cookies, including whether or not to accept them and how to remove them.

You may set most browsers to notify you if you receive a cookie, or you may choose to block cookies with your browser, but please note that if you choose to erase or block your cookies, you will need to re-enter your original user ID and password to gain access to certain parts of the web site.

Tracking technologies may record information such as Internet domain and host names; Internet protocol (IP) addresses; browser software and operating system types; clickstream patterns; and dates and times that our site is accessed. Our use of cookies and other tracking technologies allows us to improve our web site and your web experience. We may also analyze information that does not contain personal information for trends and statistics.

Our employees are subject to strict guidelines regarding confidentiality, and internal access to customer data is restricted to highly trained personnel on an "as-needed" basis.

## Transmitting Information

When transmitting information between you and our server, as well as when communicating with the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) for electronic filing, data security is handled through a protocol called Secure Sockets Layer (SSL). SSL is an established and mature Internet security standard with two dominant features: web server authentication and data encryption.

top

## Data Encryption

Data encryption is the process of transforming legible information into a complex arrangement of illegible information. SSL uses a private/public key combination to encrypt data when it is sent and to decrypt data when it is received. SSL encrypts data using a mathematical formula, also referred to as a "key."

Encryption strength is measured by the length of the key used to encrypt the data; the longer the key, the more effective the encryption. Using the SSL protocol, data transmission between you and our web server is performed at a standard level of encryption strength.

## Web Server Authentication

An SSL certificate is issued to ensure authentic and accurate identification of a secured web server. This translates into a digital ID, an electronic fingerprint, which is included in the key used to encrypt the data. Only our web server, in this case, is able to decrypt the data that you transmit because it is the intended (and digitally certified) secured web server for this data transmission.

## The Information We Collect

This Policy applies to all information collected or submitted on our web site. If a credit card is used to pay for the Service, in addition to tax return information, we collect the following credit card and personal information:

  * Cardholder's Name
  * Credit Card Type
  * Credit Card Number
  * Expiration Date
  * Cardholder's Billing Address
  * Daytime Phone Number
  * E-mail Address
  * Employer's or Relative's Phone Number

The credit card information is used to process your transaction. This information is not made available to anyone else.

We also collect the following information for use in answering your inquiries for technical support when you submit an email requesting our assistance:

  * Your name
  * User ID
  * E-mail Address
  * Phone Number
  * Operating System
  * Browser Type
  * Connection type/speed

top

## The Way We Use Information

The tax return information that we collect is used strictly for lawful purposes and is never shared with federal, state, or other taxing authorities without your consent. The foregoing notwithstanding, we reserve the right to disclose your information without your consent in response to a court order, subpoena, search warrant, or other inquiry or request from governmental or regulatory authorities, or to protect against fraud or other criminal activities. If you choose to electronically file your return, we will transmit your tax return to the appropriate federal and state taxing authorities.

The IRS requires us to provide the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer from which the return originated, as well as the e-mail address of the person who electronically filed the return. This information is sent to the IRS at the time you choose to submit your return to the IRS for electronic filing.

In order to electronically file your return, we must share your submitted tax information with the appropriate tax authorities in order to complete your request. You can control whether or not you wish your tax information shared for this purpose by deciding whether or not to complete the tax returns forms, which are all clearly labeled.

The above listed credit card information that we collect will be used strictly for order processing and billing purposes, and will not be shared with any other party. When appropriate, bank account or credit card information is also passed to our bank for processing purposes. You will enter this information during the routine course of a purchase. In the event that our internet service staff should need to research and resolve any status or billing issues associated with an order, the information will only be accessed by authorized personnel.

Our Basic Service entitles you to notification via e-mail of filing deadlines, estimate reminders, tax law changes, as well as tax planning and financial information that may affect your tax return. In order for us to provide you with the Basic Service, it is required that you provide us with your e-mail address and consent to our limited review of your tax return information with our proprietary software program to determine whether your tax return information would trigger such notifications.

In addition to our Basic Service, we may send to you, via your e-mail address, information and promotional messages about other products and services that we think may be of interest to you.

Personally identifiable information is only shared as indicated in this document. Any sharing of such information is subject to the opt-out option as discussed in the paragraph below.

top

## Consent to Use Information

By using this web site, you consent to the terms or our Online Privacy Policy and to eFile processing personal information for the purposes given above, as well as those explained where eFile collects personal information on the web.

Should the Online Privacy Policy change, we intend to take every reasonable step to ensure that these changes are brought to your attention by posting all changes prominently on our web site for a reasonable period of time.

Your use of this service means that you consent to our limited access and review of your tax return information necessary to provide you with the Basic Service described above.

In addition, we may provide you with promotional messages. You will have the option to opt-out of receiving such promotional messages. Declining to receive e-mail promotional messages will not affect our ability to deliver our basic service to you.

## Third Party Services

For the purpose of providing you with additional information or services, our web site also provides links or references to our other web sites or to third party web sites of online information providers, advertisers, and other business partners. When offering partner services the partner who will be receiving your information will be clearly identified.

We are not responsible for information gathered by third party web sites. You should review any third party sites' Privacy Policy for details regarding their policies concerning information they gather. Any time you are preparing to navigate to a site that is not covered by this Privacy Policy, we will indicate at the bottom of the page that you are leaving our site.

When you select to have your tax refund transferred to your bank account, your refund will be processed on behalf of EFILE by U.S. Treasury.  You authorize us to disclose your relevant bank information to Republic Bank & Trust Company. Your indication within the program that you wish to either deduct your tax preparation fee from your tax refund or have your refund transferred to your bank account as your authorization. When you select the option within our program for a bank product (e-collect or Deduct Fee From Refund - DFFR), once your return has qualified for electronic filing we share your name, address, Social Security number, phone number, and other tax related information necessary for Bancorp and EPS Financial Services to provide the requested service. Bancorp and EPS Financial Services uses the personally identifiable information for the purpose of providing your bank product. You may [view their Privacy Policy here](https://www.epsfinancial.net/site/CheckApplicationStatus.aspx).

Through a third party partnership with Official Payments Corporation®, you may request to pay your balance due via credit or debit card. When you make this request, you authorize us to disclose your relevant credit card and tax return information to Official Payments Corporation. When you select the option within our program to pay your balance due via credit or debit card, and your return has qualified for electronic filing, we then share your name, address, Social Security number, phone number, and other tax related information necessary for Official Payments Corporation to provide the requested service. In addition, you will be asked to disclose your card information to Official Payments. Official Payments uses the personally identifiable information for the purpose of providing the payment of your tax via credit or debit card as requested. You may visit the site at www.officialpayments.com to view their Privacy Policy.

Information entered into the Tax Calculators (through Time Value Software) is used solely to provide you with estimates of various tax situations. The information used in these calculations is not saved. You may visit the site at www.tvalue.com to view their Privacy Policy.

top

## Retrieving Your Information

Our Service is available for starting, completing, and efiling your return from approximately mid-January through mid-October of each tax year. To view your return information, you may use your User ID and Password to access a free summary report and/or pay a fee to print, view, and electronically file your actual return. Once you have paid, you may continue to access, modify, and/or print your tax return as often as needed during this time.

From mid-October through mid-December you can still complete and mail your return to the appropriate filing authorities if you began it prior to mid-October.

After paying for your return, the financial information used to make your payment, such as your credit card number, as well as the record of your payment, will not be retrievable by you.

## Disclaimer

EFILE reserves the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe such disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served through our web site.

## How to Contact Us

Should you have other questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please submit your questions using our Customer Support Page or one of the methods below.

> EFILE LLC  
>  Email: support@efile.com  
>  Web site: <http://www.efile.com/>

top

Start a Tax Return

  * No Risk
  * No Registration
  * Maximum Refund Faster

> "I have had a great experience with efile.com. Thank you for another great tax year!"  
>  Mike (US Marine)

> "Wow, this was so easy and not time consuming either."  
>  Lisa in Portland
